http://www.equinenow.com/privacy.htm

PRIVACY NOTICE
Effective Date: August 28, 2005
Revised: May 24, 2017
Our Commitment To Privacy
EquineNow.com, LLC (“we,” “our,” “us”) respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it through our compliance
with this Privacy Policy. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online data collection,
processing and usage practices, and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. This
Privacy Policy applies to our group of websites, including EquineNow.com, DogsNow.com, BirdsNow.com, LocaRVs.com,
LocalBikeTrader.com, MyBoatsForSale.com, CatsNow.com, InstrumentWire.com, ReptilesNow.com, LivestockNow.com, and IronDiets.com ("Websites"). To
make this notice easy to find, we make it available as a link in the footer of our Websites. We reserve the right to change this
Privacy Policy at any time, so refer back often to read the most current version.
The Information We Collect, Why We Collect It, and How We Collect It
We may collect the following types of data about you when you use the Websites: 1. Personal Information; 2. Communication Information;
3. User Contribution Information; 4. Navigational Information; and 5. Payment Information.
Personal Information is information that you voluntarily submit to us and identifies you personally when you fill out
forms on our Websites, and may also be included in the other types of data described below. This includes, but is not limited to,
your name, address, phone number, email address, business name, and other information about you or your business when creating
an account on the Websites, at the time of subscribing to any of our services, or when using our online support system. We may
also ask you for information if we receive a complaint about you. Personal Information can also include information about any
transactions, both free and paid, that you enter into on the Websites, and information about you that is available on the Internet,
such as from Facebook, Twitter and Google, or publicly available information that we may acquire.
Communication Information is collected if you contact us using the online support system, or by direct email.
We may keep a record of that correspondence. The information we collect will include the details of the messages you send
and receive using our internal support service including, without limitation, the date/time you sent or received a message and the
contents of that message.
User Contribution Information is collected when you add, edit, delete, or upload information to the Websites. Information we
collect may include, but is not limited to, IP address, browser information, computer hardware and operating system information,
text or images you might add, edit or delete, and account identifier information which can be used to link to your Personal
Information.
You are free to explore the Websites without entering any personal information about yourself. When you visit the Websites
in this manner, we collect Navigational Information.
Navigational Information includes details of your visits to the Websites including, but not limited to, browser
information, computer hardware and operating system information, geographical location data,
IP address, length of visit, pages viewed, referral source, and other communication data. Although we do not correlate tracking
information to individuals, some information collected, such as IP addresses, will be unique.
We may also collect account
identifier information which can be used to link to your Personal Information.
The Payment Information we collect and process
when you purchase any of our paid services, includes credit card numbers and billing information. Credit cards are processed
using third-party PCI-compliant service providers.
Children Under the Age of 13
The Websites are not intended for or targeted at children under 13, and we do not knowingly or intentionally collect information
about children under 13. If you believe that we have collected information about a child under 13, please contact us at
support@equinenow.com, so that we may delete the information.
The Way We Use Your Information
In addition to uses explained elsewhere in this Privacy Policy, we use the Personal Information you provide to us to
process a payment, identify you for login purposes, identify you for support purposes, and to assist us in administering
your user account. We also may send you information about our services or communicate with you about your account with us. We do
not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete a payment or for complying with
court orders or other law enforcement requests.Communication Information is used for support services for the Websites, and to contact you about your account or
our services from time to time. We may (but are not obligated to) view the contents of any email or message sent to us
by you or others, whether or not you have viewed its contents. Messages or emails sent to us are not private and are
not confidential. Email addresses are not shared with outside parties.
User Contribution Information is used for support services, tracking and logging user contributions to the Websites,
quality control purposes, and to allow for other administrative purposes that might arise from time to time.
Navigational Information is used to operate the Websites, improve navigation, track user tendencies, and allow for
other administrative purposes that might arise from time to time.
If you give us Payment Information such as credit card information, we use it solely to collect payment from you.
We use a third-party service provider to manage credit card processing. This service provider is not permitted to
store, retain, or use information you provide except for the sole purpose of credit card processing on our behalf.
Disclosure of Your Information
We may disclose aggregated information about our users, and information that does not identify any individual, without
restriction. We may disclose information about you that we collect or you provide:
To contractors, service providers, and other third parties we use to support our business.
To a buyer or other successor in the event of a merger, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or
transfer of some or all of the Company’s assets, in which personal information held by the Company is
among the assets transferred.
To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it.
For any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information.
To comply with any court order, law, or legal process, including to respond to any
government or regulatory request.Our Websites may also include public forums or blogs. Please keep
in mind that if you directly disclose any information through our public blogs or forums, this information
may be collected and used by others and you are responsible for any post you might make. We may correct or
delete any information you have posted on the Websites if you so request, unless its deletion is in
violation of our Terms of Use (link found in the footer of our Websites). Please email support@equinenow.com
with your request.
Finally, we never use or share the Personal Information you provide to us in ways unrelated to the ones
described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated
uses.
Third-Party Websites
Our Websites may provide links to other websites. We do not control, and are not responsible for, the content or
practices of these other websites. Our provision of such links does not constitute our endorsement of these other
websites, their content, their owners, or their practices. This Privacy Policy also does not apply to these other
websites. Please refer to the other websites for any privacy policy they may have.
Cookies
The Websites use cookies. By using the Websites, you consent to our use of cookies. Cookies are small text files
that are sent to web browsers by web servers, saved on a user's computer, and which may then be sent back to the web
server when the browser requests a web page. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more
efficiently, as well as to provide information to the web server to identify and track users as they navigate to
different web pages on a web site, as well as identify users returning to a web site. Cookies may either be persistent
or session cookies. Persistent cookies are stored by the browser and will remain until they expire or are deleted
by a user. A session cookie will expire at the end of a user session, when the browser is closed. We use both
persistent and session cookies. None of our cookies store any credit/debit card information nor password details.
Cookies do not contain information that personally identifies you. However, Personal Information that you provide and
we store about you may be linked, by us, to information stored in and obtained from cookies. Cookies we use on the
Websites are those which are necessary for access and navigation, track usage, remember your preferences, and
provide you with targeted content or advertising. We may use the information we obtain from your use of the
Websites and cookies to: 1. Recognize your computer when you visit our Websites; 2. Track your use as you navigate
through the Websites; 3. Enhance the Websites's usability; 4. Administration of the Websites; and 5. Personalize
the Websites for you, including targeting advertisements.
At this time the Websites do not recognize automated browser signals regarding tracking mechanisms, which may include
"do not track" instructions. However, you can change your privacy preferences regarding the use of cookies
and similar technologies through your browser. You may set your browser to accept all cookies, block certain cookies,
require your consent before a cookie is placed in your browser, or block all cookies. Blocking all cookies will affect
your online experience and may prevent you from enjoying the full features offered on our Websites. Please consult the
"Help" section of your browser for more information.
Advertising Cookies
Some of our advertising partners may use cookies on our site. Our advertising partners may include: (1) Google Ad
Exchange; (2) Criteo; (3) Komoona; (4) Sovrn; (5) District M; (6) Sekindo; (7) Carbon Media Group; (8) Roxot;
(9) Vertoz; (10) Amazon; and (11) Sonobi.
Advertising partners may be removed, and others may be added, from time to time.
Third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on your prior visits to the Websites or other
websites. Google’s use of advertising cookies enables it and its partners to serve ads to you based on your visit to
the Websites and/or other websites on the Internet. Third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology in the advertisements
and links that appear on our Websites to send ads directly to your browser. They automatically receive your IP address
when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies or JavaScript) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to
measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see. Our Websites
has no access to, or control over, these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers. A list of typical technology partners
for third-party vendors and a link to their respective privacy policy, can be found here. You
should consult the respective
privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions
about how to opt-out of certain practices. This privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of,
advertisers or other websites.
If you wish to disable or delete cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information
about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites. You may learn
about opting-out of personal advertising by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following
URL – http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html. Alternately, you may learn about opting-out of a third-party advertiser’s use
of cookies for personalized advertising by visiting http://www.aboutads.info/choices/.
Log Files
Our web servers record certain requests and transactions in log files. This log data is used for operation of the Websites,
to maintain the quality of the Websites, troubleshooting, statistics, analytics, and to monitor system security and can be analyzed
to that end. There is also information about your computer hardware, operating system, and software that is automatically collected by
us in log files. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, internet service provider (ISP), the
files viewed on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, clickstream data, access times, and referring website
addresses.
We also log User Contribution Information. This log data can include your IP address, browser type, computer hardware and
operating system information, details of the user contributions, and your account identifier. Your account identifier is linked
to your Personal Information.
Our Commitment to Data Security
We secure the Personal Information you provide on computer servers within an infrastructure that puts strong safeguards
in place to help protect customer privacy. All data is stored in data centers with a highly secure, controlled environment.
When sensitive Personal Information (such as a credit card number and/or geo-location data) is collected on our Websites
and/or transmitted to other websites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL)
protocol. In addition, some areas of the Websites are inaccessible unless you login using a username or email address, and your
password. Also, we do not store your complete credit card number or card code on our servers.
How You Can Access, Correct or Remove Your Information
You can access your Personal Information that we store by logging into your account through our Websites. Please be certain
that you are logging in through our Websites and not through a “phishing” website masquerading as our Websites. Doing so will
allow the phishing website to know your login credentials and then gain access to your account on our Websites. If you have
forgotten your password, there is a password reset link on the login page. Once you are logged in, you will be able to correct
any information that we store on your account dashboard page.
If you would like to have your account and Personal Information deleted, please contact us at support@equinenow.com, or by mail
at EquineNow.com, LLC, 345 S. Coast Highway Ste M2, Encinitas, CA 92024.
Retention of Personal Information
We retain Personal Information that you provide us as long as we consider it potentially useful in contacting you about our
services. We also may retain your Personal Information as needed to comply with legal obligations or resolve disputes. We may
retain user contribution or other system log files indefinitely that might be linked to your Personal information.
Changes to our Privacy Policy
We will post any changes we make to our privacy policy on this page and they will go into effect immediately upon posting.
Contact Us
Should you have other questions or concerns about this privacy policy, please send us an email to support@equinenow.com.
